This month we've been talking about
um
positioning.
Uncommon positioning. And today I want
to talk about the impact of spirit-led
investment.
Because in that positioning, God invests
in us, but also we have to put an
investment. And we are reading about the
story of the disciples
who were threatened by the religious
leaders, and then they came together and
they prayed. And this is what they
prayed.
"Now, Lord,
consider their threats
and enable your servants to speak your
word with great boldness.
Stretch out your hand to heal and
perform signs and wonders through the
name of your holy servant Jesus."
After they prayed,
after they prayed,
the place where they were meeting was
shaken. And they were all filled with
the Holy Spirit and spoke the word of
God boldly.
All the believers were one in heart and
mind. No one claimed that any of their
possession was their own, but they
shared everything they had.
Uh with great power, the apostles
continued to testify to the resurrection
of the Lord Jesus, and God's grace was
so powerfully at work in them all. This
is the word of God, and God's people say
it.
Amen. Please be seated
as we pray.
Father, even as we invite
uh this congregation to hear your word,
we also inviting those who are online,
those who are in uh the various spaces
in parkade, in the pavilion, in the
parents' room, and even later when this
message will be uh recorded and listened
to.
We want to pray that Father that this
word will be will minister in their into
their spirits, into their hearts.
We especially want to thank you because
the Bible says man shall not live by
bread alone, but by every word that
proceeds from the mouth of God. Father,
I'm your servant and even as I open this
word, may the Holy Spirit then take it
and minister to each one of us
regardless of the situations and the
circumstances we are facing. The Lord,
this word will become food to us, will
inspire us, will encourage us, will set
us up
for greater days in this coming week.
And Father, we thank you.
You're a good God. You're an awesome
God.
And we submit ourselves to the ministry
of the Holy Spirit through the word.
This we have prayed in Jesus' name. And
God's people say it.
Amen. Amen. Just to bring a report to
you also.
Uh last week we were talking about
passports. Tell your neighbor passports.
Now, I said how many people must get
passport? The first what?
First 10. And it it was important that
it was the first 10.
We got an overflow and we had 11.
Tell your neighbor 11.
Now, there are others who came with all
kinds of reasons.
Uh others had already gotten their
passport, had paid for their passports
the last week.
And they wanted a refund.
Uh tell your neighbor, these are parky
people.
But we thank God they tried and they did
their best. And we want you to get
passport uh so that you can experience
what God has in store for us across the
world. Passports will not take you to
heaven.
Uh just tell your neighbor passports
will not take you to heaven.
But will take you to Kigali.
Amen.
Uh we were able to get to the first 10
and then there were there was one more.
And I really want to appreciate the
members of this church who We
exactly that day.
And they said they were going to be part
of that refund.
And all the 11
um have been
refunded.
Uh the first nine were already refunded
last this past this past week. Uh the
other two, somebody sent money today and
they'll be sorted. And we we just thank
God for these members. So, let's
appreciate all these members who have
engaged
in a powerful way.
So, we thank God. We thank God for the
way you just connect and come through.
Look at your neighbor and tell your
neighbor, "This is an investment."
Amen.
And I'm talking about spirit-led
investment.
As we've been talking about positioning
and even last week when uh Deacon Timo
was talking about how God was able to
maneuver his will and purpose and take a
girl who was a Moabite and bring her
into Israel, that was an investment.
But in that story in the book of Ruth,
Ruth had to make a decision to be part
of that investment.
And that is when she was able to tell
Naomi, "Where you go,
I will go." Then she said something key
because she was a Moabite. She said,
"Your people
shall be my people." That was a big
jump. And then she said, "Your God
shall be my God." And in the investments
that God makes in our lives, there's a
part we need to play. It's making a
decision, making a choice, and allowing
him to move in our lives uh because God
is is not just moving. When God is
moving, he wants you to move with him.
When God has made a decision, he wants
you to agree with him in that decision.
And that is why the Bible says, "For God
so loved the world." He was the one
loving the world. "For God so loved the
world," then he did something. He gave
his only begotten son. That was an
investment. Then he says there was a
part for us to do. That whosoever, that
is us, whosoever believes
His part was to give his son. Our part
was to believe in that son. Whosoever
believes in him should not perish, but
have eternal life. The verse 17
of that chapter says this, "For God did
not send his son into the world to do
what?"
To condemn the world. Jesus did not just
come to see the wrong things we have
done and kill us.
For God did not send his son into the
world to condemn the world,
but to save the world through him. Verse
18 says, "Whoever believes, that is
anybody, whoever believes in him is not
condemned, but whoever does not believe
stands condemned already because they
have not believed in the name of God's
one and only son." So, God made an
investment. But in making an investment,
he also wanted us to make an investment
by believing him, by trusting him, by
walking with him in this life.
The disciples in the Bible, God made a
great investment in them. He called them
one by one and he said, "Follow me and
I'll make you fishers of men." And they
followed him.
And then there is something that they
began to do. There are things that they
invested in so that the church would
grow and the church would multiply and
the church would have an effect in the
world today. They made an investment.
That is why we are here today. If these
disciples had not invested, some of
them, most of them were killed and died
for their faith, but we are alive today
because they did something. But during
their time, they made investments in
three ways and I want to talk about
those three things this afternoon.
Number one, they made an investment
prevailing prayer.
Number two, they made an investment
through propelling faith.
And they made an investment through
persistent proclamation.
And because they did this, our lives
have been changed. I want to talk about
the first one, prevailing prayer. They
these these men prayed and prayed. And
and and because they prayed, God did
amazing things.
In the book of Acts, the one that you
read, I want to read it from verse 23,
because they had been threatened
for preaching the gospel, somebody had
been healed, and now they were being
threatened that if they continue
preaching like this, uh their lives are
going to be curtailed, they're going to
be stopped. The Bible says, "On their
release,
Peter and John went back to their own
people and reported all that the chief
priests and the elders had said to
them."
When they heard this,
when they heard this,
they raised their voices together in
prayer to God. You know, sometimes when
there's a crisis in your life, and a
situation is coming that you're being
threatened, and your life is just about
to be brought to an end, instead of
coming and doing what they did, you call
you call people, you get scared, uh you
get a committee together, and all kinds
of things. But these guys got together
and did what?
Prayed. Tell your neighbor, prayer is
key.
And they and they prayed and and their
prayer was a prevailing prayer. Because
sometimes people pray and pray for a
long time, and they don't prevail.
And you wonder, "I've been praying for
this thing for a long time, and I'm not
prevailing." But these guys prevailed.
Now, see what they said.
It says, "When they heard this, they
raised their voices together in prayer
to God." And listen to how they said it.
They said, "Sovereign Lord." They knew
who they were talking to. They were not
talking to a person who was defeated,
they were talking to a person who was
already victorious. Sovereign Lord. They
said, "You made the heavens
and the earth and the sea and everything
in them.
You spoke by the Holy Spirit through the
mouth of your servant, our father David.
Why do the nations rage and the peoples
plot in vain? The kings of the earth
rise up and the rulers band together
against the Lord and against his
anointed one. Indeed, Herod and Pontius
Pilate met together with the Gentiles
and the people of Israel in this city to
conspire against your holy servant
Jesus, whom you anointed.
They did what your power and will had
decided beforehand should happen. Now
Lord, now listen to how they're praying.
Consider their threats
and enable your servants to speak. Uh he
didn't he doesn't say, "Consider their
threats
and God help us to escape from this
city."
They said, "Enable your servants to
speak your word with great boldness.
Stretch out your hand to heal and
perform signs and wonders through the
name of your holy servant Jesus." And
the Bible says in that short prayer,
after they prayed, God answered
immediately. Let me tell you this, when
you prevail in prayer, God answers
immediately. God doesn't wait for you.
God knows you've come through for him.
God wants to answer your prayer
immediately. The place where they were
meeting was shaken and they were all
filled with the Holy Spirit and spoke
the word of God boldly. They prevailed
in prayer. But you know, sometimes you
ask yourself, "Why don't I prevail in
prayer? Why don't I prevail? Because the
way you uh you uh you uh you approach
prayer is not the right way.
Let me talk about this widow. The Bible
talks about prayer and a widow and a and
and a judge. A widow is very weak. The
judge is very strong, but she prevailed.
Look at this scripture in Luke chapter
18 of a widow who was in a disadvantaged
state, but was able to prevail with this
judge.
The Bible says in verse one,
Then Jesus told his disciples a parable
to show them them they to show them that
they should always pray, always pray,
always pray.
Always pray.
Always complain.
Always cry.
Always pray and not
give up.
And then the Bible says he said in a
certain town, "There was a judge who
neither feared God nor cared what people
thought. And there was a widow, a weak
lady in that town who kept coming to him
with a plea, 'Grant me justice against
my adversary.'"
For some time he refused. But finally he
said to himself, "Even though I don't
fear God or care what people think, yet
because this widow keeps bothering me, I
will see that she gets justice so that
she won't eventually come and attack
me." She got He got scared.
And the Lord said, "Listen to what the
unjust judge says."
And the Bible says, "And will not God"
You see now God is not comparing himself
to that judge. God is a God who hears
you. God is quick quick to give you
justice. And God is saying, "Hey, I'm
not that bad judge. I'm the good judge.
And will not God bring about justice
for his chosen ones
who cry out to him day and night? Will
he keep putting them off? No, I tell
you, he will see that they get justice
and quickly." Somebody's going to get
justice quickly.
I'm saying somebody's going to get
The Bible says, "However, when the Son
of Man comes, will he find faith on the
earth?"
And God is looking for men and women who
will prevail with him in prayer. And you
know, prevailing prayer brings about
supernatural encounters.
Sometimes our the churches have been so
organized
until we don't need the supernatural.
Hello?
Let me tell you this, God himself is
supernatural.
God himself is very different. He's not
in the natural realm. God is in the
supernatural realm.
And I want to tell you this,
when we begin to pray, the moment you
just say our father,
you enter into a supernatural realm.
When you say in the name of Jesus, I
come to you today, Lord,
you enter into the supernatural realm.
And only the supernatural realm answers
to people like that. And I'm telling
you, there are situations that you go
through, even today, that require a
supernatural engagement, a supernatural
encounter.
Hallelujah.
I'm telling you, some of those things
are landlord issues. Hallelujah.
Ah, landlord issues. Ah, your landlord
is after you and you're you're in
arrears. And one day you you just
finished then you go to God and say,
"Oh, Jehovah God, you are a God of
abundance. You are a God who does
amazing things. Today I'm going to see
the landlord. And as I go to see the
landlord, go before me in the name of
Jesus."
And then you go to see the landlord.
By the time you reach there trying to
plead and say, "Brother, give me give me
15 more days."
The landlord tells you, "Hey, listen, I
I don't know who sent the money, but
somebody has sent your money for the
next for the next 3 months."
Come on, somebody better give God a big
hand.
You know,
that is a supernatural
encounter. God has moved on your behalf.
Before you could even finish the prayer,
God has come through for you. Because
let me tell you this, prayer is about
God coming through for you.
In Jesus' name.
Bwana asifiwe.
Peter was one guy who saw the
supernatural.
And he began to engage the supernatural,
but
he saw that in the life of Jesus.
Because Jesus, even though he was the
son of God, he was also the son of man,
and he depended on the supernatural. And
the only way he could engage the
supernatural was to spend time with God
in prayer.
Let me take you to Matthew chapter 14.
The Bible says this, chapter 14 around
verse 22. Jesus had just fed the 5,000,
and now he needed a break. The Bible
says in verse 22,
"Immediately Jesus made the disciples
get into the boat and go on ahead of him
to the other side while he dismissed the
crowd."
After he had dismissed them, he went up
on a mountain by himself. To do what?
To pray.
And he was he was going there around in
around evening time when guys were
leaving.
The Bible says, "Later that night,
he was there alone,
and the boat was already a considerable
distance from the land, buffeted by the
waves because the wind was against it."
The Bible says, "Shortly before dawn."
Now, think of the time Jesus has spent
time praying. He had just started
going to the mountain around 6:00 in the
evening.
He was going to the boat around dawn.
Around 4:00,
5:00 in the morning. So, he had been
praying the whole
time. And praying for the disciples. Of
course, he knew they were in problems,
but he was praying. But you see, the
time he spent in prayer prepared him for
the supernatural.
Hallelujah.
And and let me tell you this, if you're
going to we are going to see the
supernatural in Pakyi, we're going to
spend time in prayer a lot. If you're
going to see the supernatural in your
family, in your homes, in your
workplace, prevail with God in prayer.
The Bible says, "Shortly before dawn,
Jesus went to them walking on the lake."
Walking on the lake. Who walks on the
lake?
It's not a normal thing. You just try
walking on the lake. Uh, you're going to
sink.
The the the the the the laws of physics
do not do not will not help you.
Hello.
Because the laws of physics say this,
when a body is totally or partially
immersed in a fluid, it experiences an
upthrust which is equal to the weight of
the fluid displaced. That's the law of
physics.
Thank you, Jesus.
For some of you could Peter.
Those are the laws of physics. But Jesus
suspended the laws of physics by
spending time in what?
In prayer. You can suspend certain laws
in amazing ways because you spend time
in prayer.
But listen to this. Not only he was he
able to walk on water, he said this when
the disciples saw him walking
on the lake, they were terrified.
"It's a ghost." They said and cried out
in fear.
But Jesus immediately said to them, "Hey
guys, take courage. It is I. Don't be
afraid."
"Lord." And this is now Peter.
Now Peter was a guy
who was forward forward. You know what
that means?
Forward forward means what?
Okay? Anything happened, you know, he
just moved. He never thought twice.
Uh, he This is what he said, "Lord."
Now remember they have been very
terrified.
But then he says, "Lord, if it is you."
Peter replied, "Tell me to come to you
on the water."
Jesus said only one statement, "Come."
Then Peter got down out of the boat.
He made a choice. He made a decision.
Tell your neighbor better make a
decision.
He Peter got down out of the boat,
walked on the water. He walked. That is
a testimony. Nobody else has that
testimony.
He walked on the water towards Jesus.
Uh, but when he saw the wind,
he changed his focus. He was afraid and
beginning to think, he cried out, "Lord,
save me." Immediately Jesus reached out
his hand and caught him. "You have
little faith," he said, "why did you
doubt?" And when they climbed into the
boat, the wind died down. Let me tell
you this, the supernatural is still
happening today.
I'm talking to somebody here and I'm
saying the supernatural is still
happening today.
And you can walk on the on the waters of
your life because you prevailed in
prayer. Uh God can take you through a
situation and you by the time you go
through you wonder, "Hey, how did I pass
there?
What did what just happened?"
Sometimes God snatches you out of
accidents.
Like I was told the other day, one of
the ladies in parky
got got in an accident
on on on the on the bypass, the the
southern bypass. And there was a lorry
that was just following her and she
remember they're on the bypass where
there's a wall on this side. So they're
on the bypass and suddenly when she was
trying to avoid this lorry which is
behind her, the lorry hit her kidogo and
she flipped.
Flipped over the wall to the other side.
Kupingining, kupingining, kupingining,
kupingining
to the grass but the car went back on
its four legs.
She unbuckled.
She opened the door
and walked out.
And the people who are around were
expecting to come and pull a dead person
out of that place.
Because
the car was smashed.
Now, how she didn't know
how she came out, she does not know.
Because later when now she's looking at
the car,
she's wondering, "How did I
come out?" That's a supernatural
encounter.
Now, maybe she was not praying, but
somebody somewhere
maybe a mother
or an aunt or a friend.
God just tied them and said, "Pray for
so-and-so."
And maybe they did were not praying at
that time. Maybe they prayed even when
the lady left the house. That's when
they started praying because God went
ahead of her
and the angels of the Lord
covered her
while she was rolling in that car and
she came out. The supernatural.
Take your I'll tell your neighbor,
"Prevailing prayer."
Tell your other neighbor, "Prevailing
prayer."
You see, one of the ways to pray
prevailing prayer is to pray like a
champion, not like a victim.
When you pray like a victim, God never
answers your prayer. When you pray like
a victim, you're saying, "Oh God, why?
Why? God this and that. God, you should
have come to me." And you're all you're
doing is complaining, but champions
don't complain. Champions say,
"Sovereign Lord."
The moment you say, "Sovereign Lord,"
God comes through for you.
God connects. And prayer is important.
And so prevail in prayer in the name of
Jesus. I'm talking to somebody and say,
"Prevail in prayer in Jesus' name."
Now, of course, some people when they
pray, they pray because of things that
don't matter. Now, let me read you this
verse in the book of James because
sometimes we we pray wrongly. And so,
even though we pray, we God doesn't
answer. Look at James chapter 4 verse 1.
The Bible says this about prayer. And
prayer is an act. This is something that
you have to learn and grow into. It
says, "What causes fights and quarrels
among you? Don't they come from your
desires that battle within you?
The Bible says it says, "You desire, but
you do not have.
So, what do you do?
You kill.
You covet, but you cannot get what you
want. So, you quarrel and fight.
You do not have
because
you do not ask God. So, sometimes you
just don't have because you never asked.
But then look at the next verse.
But when you ask
you do not
receive
because you ask with the wrong motives.
That you may spend what you get on your
pleasures.
So, you know, there's a way you can pray
and God will not answer. You You will
not prevail at all.
Sometimes when we pray, we pray with
fear. We are scared.
We are anxious.
Uh look at Philippians chapter 4 verse
6. The Bible says when you pray, don't
pray with worry in your system. It says,
"Do not be
anxious." So, when you're praying, don't
come with anxiety. Uh but bring your
anxiety to God. Do not be anxious about
anything. But in every situation
by prayer
and petition with thanksgiving, present
your requests to God.
And the peace of God
which transcends
all understanding will guard your hearts
and your minds in Christ
Jesus.
And then remember to think about the
right things. Look at the next verse.
The next verse he says, "After you have
prayed
please, brothers and sisters, whatever
is true
whatever is noble
whatever is right whatever is pure
whatever is lovely whatever is
admirable, if anything is excellent or
praiseworthy
think about such things." So, don't pray
with anxiety and worry. And because some
of us pray with worry, worry, worry.
Then after we have prayed, we say,
"Lord, thank you for answering my
prayer." But the moment you walk out of
that door
you worry.
You're like like like that person
who carried their burden, carried their
burden. It was such a burden they come
to Jesus. "Oh, Jehovah God, I'm coming
to bring you my burden. Oh, it is a
heavy burden. It's a heavy burden that
you're God, you're God who takes burdens
from us. Cast your burdens unto Jesus.
And so Jehovah, I'm casting my burden
unto you. So you cast the burden and you
feel such relief. You say, "Oh God,
thank you.
I'm so happy. Oh, I bless you. Thank
you, Jesus. So Father, before I go, let
me carry my burden and go with it." And
so you take off and you walk around with
the burden and you did not leave there.
Look at your neighbor. Tell your
neighbor,
"Leave it there."
Tell your neighbor, "God will take care
of it."
Prevailing prayer is when you release
that prayer and you say, "I have
released it.
Let it go.
Let it go. Let it go." Amen.
But so for some people, the problem with
of not having answered prayer is very
simple. Let me read it in Mark chapter
chapter 11 verse 25. These are just
things that make you not prevail in
prayer. But this verse says this, "And
when you stand praying,
if you hold anything against anyone,
do what?"
"Forgive them."
"So that your Father in heaven may
forgive your sins."
All right? Now of course you know you
look at this Are you seeing this verse?
Look at it.
From verse 25, it jumped 27.
So where is verse 26?
It did it. So it it omitted verse 26. So
now let me read this
in the New King James version because 26
is in there. Tell your neighbor, "Amen."
That's all In the New King James
version, it says this, "And whenever you
stand praying, if you have anything
against anyone, forgive them that your
Father in heaven may also forgive your
trespasses."
Now in verse 26, it says, "But if you do
not forgive,
neither will your Father in heaven
forgive your trespasses."
Do you see that? So you won't prevail in
prayer because you're holding a grudge.
You have refused to pray.
Refused to forgive, and so God is
saying, "Fine, we will wait for you
until you forgive."
So, I'm telling you, if you're going to
prevail, please forgive your friend.
Forgive your mom. Forgive your dad.
Forgive. Forgive. Forgive.
Hallelujah.
Uh forgive your pastor.
And even when I pray, I forgive my
congregants because we offend one
another in many different ways. Just
forgive. Forgive, you will prevail in
prayer. But I wanted you to go to the
next one, propelling faith. That as you
pray and prevail in prayer, you also
have to release your faith.
And faith is mountain-moving engagement.
Look at Mark chapter 11 because there a
mountain got moved. Chapter 11 verse 20.
We'll begin it around verse 20 and pick
it from there. The Bible says this,
"In the morning, because Jesus had just
cast a fig tree, he says, 'The next
morning, as they went along, they saw
the fig tree withered from the roots.'"
Peter remembered and said to Jesus,
"Rabbi, look,
the fig tree you cast has withered." And
Jesus said, "Hey, have faith in God."
Jesus answered, "Truly, I tell you, if
anyone says to this mountain, 'Go throw
yourself into the sea,' and does not
doubt in their heart, but believes that
what
but believes that what they say will
happen, it will be done for them." Now,
it is important that in this verse,
Pastor Felista, it says, "Don't tell God
about your mountain.
Tell your mountain
about your God."
Hallelujah.
Because many times we tell God about
the mountain. That's the first thing.
Because the mountain is so
big. It's it it it is it's so
intimidating. Uh
but when the psalmist is praying he
says, "I look up to the mountain. Where
does my help
come from?" And then he said, "My help
does not come from this mountain. My
help comes from the Lord,
the maker of heaven and earth."
And let me tell you this, your mountain
can be moved.
I'm saying your mountain can be moved.
In that chapter it says this,
"The sun will not smite you
by day, nor the moon by night."
Uh, and then and then in the King James
it says, "Your foot shall not sleep."
Some Bible says, "Your foot shall not be
removed."
And you have heard me give you the story
of this missionary
who was in Kenya one time, and he had a
big problem with his foot.
And when he went to Nairobi Hospital,
they told him, "By the way, this foot
has to be removed."
And so he went to the hospital, he was
so he was so devastated. Uh, you know, a
a pastor needs his two feet.
Tell your neighbor, "Amen."
I was so devastated. Nobody could
encourage him. And you know, sometimes
it's very difficult to encourage pastors
because they know everything. Hello?
So people could encourage this man, and
encourage him and say, "Don't worry, God
will come through for you. God will come
through for you." Uh, he was not being
encouraged. He's in hospital. He's going
to be operated the next day.
So in the next day,
uh, as they're waiting, this lady, the
old lady comes to the the the the
pastor's at the at the at the bed. And
he says, "Pastor, I want to read you a
verse."
So the lady the lady reads that verse.
"I look up to the mountains. Where does
my help come from?" And the pastor
already has decided, "I know that verse.
I have preached from that verse.
I know every area of that verse." So the
pastor is not listening, but the lady is
reading.
"I look up to the mountain. Where does
my help come from? My help comes from
the Lord, the maker of heaven and earth.
And the pastor says, "I know that. The
sun will not smite you by day, nor the
moon by night. The Lord will watch over
you." And then she read this part where
it woke the pastor up. He says, "Your
foot shall not be moved."
She said, "Eh, read read read read that
again."
"What did you just read?"
Now, the lady doesn't know that is that
sentence is making a lot of difference.
She says, "Your foot shall not be
moved."
You know, the pastor grabbed that verse
like
it was his last hope.
And he got so excited because suddenly
what God was telling him was this,
"This foot you're planning to get moved
tomorrow, it will not
be moved."
And he believed God. And suddenly he
became very joyful. He told that lady,
"Thank you for coming. I'm so glad you
read this verse for me. I've never seen
this verse like this."
When the doctors came just to prepare
him for the next day, he was so happy.
They said, "Pastor, you're so happy
today." He said, "Yeah, I'm so happy."
"Why?" "Because there's another doctor
who just came here and he told me that
my foot will not be moved."
So, they're asking, "Which doctor is
that? Does he work here at Nairobi
Hospital?" He says, "No, you know, but
he visited." "Uh, what is his name?"
"He's called Dr. Jesus."
"What did he say?" "My foot will not be
moved." And the doctor thought this guy
was becoming hysterical. He needed some
more injections just to make sure he
calms down,
uh, things like that. But do you know,
through that night
God worked on that foot.
The next day, when they just came and
did an x-ray or two just to get him
ready, there was nothing wrong with that
foot.
Nothing wrong with that foot.
He walked out of Nairobi Hospital and
his foot
was not moved.
That's the God we serve.
That's the God you serve.
But it took faith.
And faith comes by what?
By hearing. So, the pastor got to hear a
word he preaches all the time, but he
had it differently because, ladies and
gentlemen, faith does not come by
praying.
Faith does not come by singing.
Faith does not come by clapping.
Faith does not come by crying.
You can cry all the day, but when faith
comes, it comes by hearing.
And what must you hear?
The word of God. And when you hear that
word, you know
it shall be well.
And I'm speaking to somebody here and
saying this, as this word is coming to
you,
believe God.
Believe God.
Because this word
is a very powerful word.
It's a mountain moving word.
And I'm telling you God will change your
life.
I'm saying God will change your life. In
the book of Acts, there are different
gates that were moved because of faith.
The first gate was in Acts chapter 3.
So, let me go just through that quickly
as we summarize this word today. There's
a gate and some of you may be in some
gates that need to be shaken and
changed. The Bible says in chapter 1,
one day Peter and John were going up to
the temple at the time of prayer, at
3:00 in the afternoon.
Now, a man who was lame from birth was
being carried to the temple where?
To the temple
gate. And some of us may have come to
through the gate of the church and
you're in the temple gates. And the
Bible says
uh that gate was called beautiful, where
he was put every day to beg from those
going into the temple courts.
When he saw Peter and John about to
enter, he asked them for money.
Because sometimes we think that money
will solve our situation. But let me
tell you this, money is important, but
there are things money cannot
do. Peter looked straight at him
and so did John John. Then Peter said,
"Look at us."
So the man gave them his attention
expecting to get something from them.
Then Peter said, "Silver or gold I do
not have.
But what I do have, I give you. In the
name of Jesus Christ of Nazareth, walk."
Taking him by the right hand, he helped
him up and instantly the man's feet and
ankles became strong. He jumped to his
feet and began to walk. Then he went
with them into the temple courts walking
and jumping
and praising God.
Much later, some people asked, "How did
you do this?" Now go to verse 16. This
is what Peter said.
He said this, verse 16,
being questioned, "Why did you do this
to this man?" Peter said, "By faith in
the name of Jesus,
this man whom you see and know was made
strong. It is Jesus' name and the faith
that comes through him that has
completely healed him as you all can
see."
Tell your neighbor, "Prevailing
prayer." Tell your neighbor, "Propelling
faith."
That was one of the gates. Let me take
you to another gate. Acts chapter 12.
The Bible says this, it was a miracle
out of a gate. And it says this in
chapter 12,
verse one. It was about this time that
King Herod arrested some who belonged to
the church intending to persecute them.
He had James, the brother of John, put
to death with a sword.
When he saw that this met with approval
among the Jews, he proceeded to seize
Peter.
Also, this happened during the Festival
of the Unleavened Bread.
After arresting him, he put him in
prison handing him over to be guarded by
four squads of four soldiers each.
Herod intended
to bring them out for public trial after
the Passover.
So, Peter was kept in prison, but guess
what what the church was doing. What was
the church doing?
They were honestly praying. You know,
when James was killed, nobody was
praying.
James was caught,
killed. When they caught Peter, wakasema
mambo ni meharibika.
They began to pray.
So, Peter was kept in prison, but the
church was honestly praying to God for
him.
The night before Herod was to bring him
to trial, Peter was sleeping between two
soldiers bound with two chains
and sent to his two guards at the
entrance.
Tell your neighbors, "Suddenly."
>> Suddenly.
>> Now, that's what is going to happen to
some of you this week
because of your faith. Suddenly,
something is going to happen.
Your gates are going to open like this.
The Bible says, "Suddenly, an angel of
the Lord appeared and a light shone in
the cell. He struck Peter on the side
and woke him up. Quick, get up." He
said, "And the chains fell off Peter's
wrists."
Then the angel said to him, "Put on your
clothes." The guy had been sleeping so
hard. I mean, he was so much at peace.
And he was singing this song at night.
Leaning,
leaning,
leaning on the everlasting.
He had knocked out.
Though in prison.
Then the angel said to him, "Put on your
clothes and sandals." And Peter said,
"Did so." "Wrap your cloak around you
and follow me." The angel told him.
Peter followed him out of the prison,
but he had no idea
that what the angel was doing was really
happening. He thought he was seeing a
vision. You know, Peter thought that AI
was happening.
I'm telling you, this was reality. There
is There was no AI. It was serious.
They passed the first and second guards
and came to the iron gate. And I'm
talking to somebody today. It doesn't
matter what iron gate that is you're
about to go through.
Are you about to go through?
Leading to the city, it opened for them
by
itself.
And they went through.
When they had walked the length of one
street, suddenly the angel left him.
Then Peter came to himself and said,
"Now I know without a doubt that the
Lord has sent his angel and rescued me
from Herod's clutches and from
everything the Jewish people were hoping
to happen to me." Somebody is escaping
from the jails of the enemy.
I'm talking to somebody here that your
gates are open.
I'm talking to somebody that your gates
are open in Jesus' name. Your financial
gates are open in Jesus' name.
Your health gates are open in Jesus'
name.
God can do that by faith. But there was
one more guy in Acts chapter 16 and I
want to read that story about another
guy. The gates were open. Inside, there
were gates inside. The Bible says this
in verse
uh that was around verse 25. Chapter 16
verse 25, the Bible says this.
About midnight, Paul and Silas were
doing what?
Praying and then they were singing hymns
to God and the other prisoners were
listening to them. Then another suddenly
happened. Suddenly there was a such a
violent earthquake that the foundations
of the prison were shaken. At once all
the prison doors flew open and
everyone's chains came loose.
The jailer woke up.
This jailer also had been sleeping so
seriously.
How many of you have come home at the
gate and the security guy had knocked
out?
Knocked out.
I had an experience like that when I was
a bachelor when I was staying in
Parklands
and I reached this gate. I had come from
Parklands as a pastor. Nimevaa suti.
Nimefika nyumbani late kidogo after
visiting visiting. I reached the gate.
And I'm banging that that gate
and I'm banging that
The guy that guy who open is sleeping.
He's right up.
Now, what do you think I did?
I'm in a suit. What do you think I did?
I climbed over
and landed on the other side.
The guy still did not wake up.
I left him there and I went to the
house. I didn't wake him up. Maybe he he
he was leaning on the everlasting arms.
But this jailer was also asleep and
suddenly he wakes up. When he saw the
prison doors open, he drew his sword.
Was about to kill himself because he
thought the prisoners had escaped.
But Paul shouted, "Don't harm yourself.
We are here." The jailer called for
lights, rushed in and fell trembling
before Paul and Silas.
He then brought them
asked, "Sirs,
what must I do
to be saved?"
They replied, "Believe in the Lord Jesus
and you'll be saved, you and your
household." Through such a
transformation, the Bible says then they
spoke the word of the Lord to him and to
all the others in the household.
At that hour at of the night, the jailer
took them and washed their wounds.
Then immediately he and all his
household were what?
Were baptized. That is a transformation.
Let me tell you this, when God touches
your life because of your faith, other
people will be affected.
I'm saying other people will be
affected.
So, you may be the only one who is born
again in your house. You may be the only
one who goes to church from your house.
But I'm telling you, because
the rest will follow.
Because of you, God will do such
miraculous things through you that the
others will see, and they will follow
Jesus Christ.
And some of you have those testimonies.
Some of you,
none of your family members used to come
to church, but one day you came.
And now, your entire family comes here.
Because that's the kind of God we serve.
Tell your neighbor, have faith in God.
Tell the other neighbor who is ignoring
you, have faith in God.
Hallelujah.
Your business is going to ex- to
explode. It's going to flourish.
In the name of Jesus. That sickness is
going to be healed.
You're going to come through in Jesus'
name.
Faith comes by hearing,
and hearing the word of God.
So, if you want to be healed, read
scriptures about healing. If you want
financial breakthrough, read scriptures
about finances. If you want peace of
mind, read scriptures about peace,
because faith comes
by hearing, and hearing the word of God.
Amen.
And sometimes God will just surprise
you. He will use a verse or a scripture
that you never even thought about,
because God's word will come in a way
that you do not know. The Bible says,
God sent his word, and his word did
what?
Healed them. It will happen to you.
It will happen to you.
I'm saying it will happen to you.
But, finally, I want to talk about
persistent proclamation, where you
proclaim the word of God over and over
and over again. Persistent proclamation.
I want to read this verse in Acts 19
verse 20.
The Bible talks about uh
God's word
touching lives of these people from
Ephesus.
They were able to bring their magical
books, and all those things were burnt.
Let me read this from verse 17, and then
I'll pick it up up to verse 20. Verse
17, if you can get it from verse 10. It
says, "When when this became known to
the Jews and Greeks living in Ephesus,
they were all seized with fear, and the
name of the Lord Jesus was held in high
honor. Many of those who believed now
came and openly confessed what they had
done. A number who had practiced sorcery
brought their scrolls together and
burned them publicly.
When they calculated the value of the
scrolls, the total came to 50,000
drachmas.
In this way, the word of the Lord spread
widely and grew in power."
What I'm saying is this,
this word of God,
when constantly spoken,
when constantly proclaimed,
it brings results.
Tell your neighbor, "The word brings
results."
It is this word that brings
life-changing
situations. For example, Saul going to
kill the disciples in Damascus. Look at
this. Let me read it very quickly. It
says this in Acts chapter 9.
God's word will bring anyone
to their knees. So, let me read that
story of Acts even as we wind up this.
Meanwhile, Saul was still breathing out
murderous threats against the Lord's
disciples. He went to the high priest
and asked him for letters to the
synagogues in Damascus, so that if he
found any there who belonged to the to
the way, whether men or women, he might
take them as prisoners to Jerusalem.
As he neared Damascus on his journey,
another suddenly happened. Suddenly, a
light from heaven flashed around him.
He fell to the ground, and then he heard
a voice say to him, "Saul, Saul, why do
you persecute me?"
"Who are you, Lord?" Saul asked. "I am
Jesus, whom you are persecuting."
He replied.
"Now, get up and go into the city, and
you'll be told what you must do."
The men traveling with Saul stood there
speechless.
They heard the sound, but did not see
anyone.
Saul got up from the ground, but when he
opened his eyes, he could see nothing.
So, they led him by the hand into
Damascus. For 3 days, he was blind and
did not eat or drink anything.
In Damascus, there was a disciple named
Ananias. The Lord called to him in a
vision, "Ananias." "Yes, Lord." He
answered. The Lord told him, "Go to the
house of Judas
on Straight Street and ask for a man
from Tarsus named Saul, for he is
praying. In a vision, he has seen a man
named Ananias come and place his hands
on him to restore his sight."
"Lord," Ananias answered, "I have heard
many reports about this man and all the
harm he has done to your holy people in
Jerusalem.
And he has come here with authority from
the chief priest to arrest all who call
on your name."
But the Lord said to Ananias, and I like
this, "Go.
This man is my chosen instrument
to proclaim my name to the Gentiles and
their kings
and to people of Israel.
I will show him how much he must suffer
for my name." Then Ananias went to the
house and entered it. Placing his hands
on Saul, he said, "Brother Saul, the
Lord Jesus, who appeared to you on the
road as you were coming here, has sent
me so that you may see again and be
filled with the Holy Spirit."
Immediately, something like scales fell
from Saul's eyes and he could see again.
He got up and was baptized. And after
taking some food, he regained his
strength. Saul spent several days with
the disciples in Damascus. The Bible
says at once, he began to preach in the
synagogues that Jesus is a son of God.
Can you imagine? Somebody better give
God a big hand.
In one single encounter
a man got to hear God's voice.
He got to hear God's word.
And 3 days later
that man is preaching that gospel.
The power of the word is amazing. And
that's why even as I close, I'm saying
this.
Please
don't just let this word remain in your
shelf.
Read it.
The Bible says, but his delight is in
the law of the Lord. On his law he
meditates
day and night. He's like a tree planted
by streams of water. Uh, sending roots
its roots in the deep. Its leaf does not
wither. It bears fruit in season.
Whatever he does prospers. This book of
the law shall not depart out of your
mouth. Meditate on it day and night.
Many of us, the reason why sometimes we
don't prevail in prayer, we don't have
faith, is because we read the Bible once
a month.
Tell your neighbor, don't read the Bible
once a month.
Some of you have Bibles on your phone.
So while you're scrolling on WhatsApp,
just remember to go to your Bible app
and read the Bible.
Hallelujah.
There's an app that has been downloaded.
It's called the YouVersion Bible. And
just the other day the YouVersion Bible
celebrated a download of the app one the
the first one billion.
Can you imagine?
They hit 1,000 they hit 1 million
downloads. They hit 1 billion. And the
day when they were on the celebrating
just a few days ago, during that meeting
3 million 3 million downloads
were engaged through the YouVersion.
And I want to just thank God for the
opportunities this world has now that
they can actually connect to the word of
God. Because let me tell you this, the
best seller
the best selling book in the world is
what?
The Bible. So, read this word. I read
this Bible every day, not to prepare
sermons, but just to read it for me.
I've read this Bible and read this Bible
and read this Bible and I will still
read this Bible. I will listen to it. My
friend, I have memorized this Bible and
it still is new every time I read it.
So,
if you're going to experience
the encounters of God, invest yourself
in reading the scriptures.
Read the word. Read the word. It never
grows old. You read it again, it is
still alive. It never grows old. And I
really want to thank God that in
Parklea, that's what we preach about.
Nothing but the word of God. So, as you
stand on your feet,
just turn to your neighbor and tell your
neighbor,
"You look like a champion."
Hallelujah.
Tell your neighbor you're not a victim.
You are a champion.
Tell your neighbor, "I will pray like a
champion."
I will have faith like a champion.
I will proclaim the word of God like a
champion.
And this year,
I will finish strong.
In Jesus' name.
Tell your neighbor, "My gates are
opening.
My suddenly's are coming my way.
Next week, you may not recognize me.
I will be changed.
Renewed.
Rebuilt.
Because of the word of God.
If you don't follow me,
Nishauri yako.
I'm following Jesus.
All the way.
Somebody better give God a big hand.
Amen.
Many years ago,
many years ago, when I was at Kenya
Science,
I used to walk from Kenya Science,
and I started a Bible study
at Nairobi Hospital
with the nurses.
Hallelujah.
I invested in that Bible study.
I'll be there every week
at Nairobi Hospital.
And quite a number of those nurses
got saved. Just had a small Bible study,
and just investing my time there.
Not knowing that one day,
one day,
when I had even left the Bible study,
I'd get married to a lady who was
working at Nairobi Hospital.
Tell your neighbor, your investments are
not in vain.
Hallelujah.
God is a good God. So, keep investing in
prayer. Invest in faith. Invest in
proclaiming the word of God. And I'm
telling you, it will accrue interest,
and God will come back to you pressed
down, shaken together, and running over.
Receive that in Jesus' name.
Did you learn something today?
So, at at least take some time and smile
at your neighbor.
Just smile. Give them invest a smile
into their lives.
Just invest, invest, invest. Invest.
What else do you feel?
You know, one time and I'm about to pray
because this is serious.
One time there's a there's a couple I
met and I was talking to them and I
asked them, "How did you meet?"
Uh cuz I like hearing those stories. How
did you meet?
So, one of them says one of them says,
"By the way, we you we used to come to
Parkland. We are still coming to
Parkland. And there's one time, Ambrose,
you said, 'Look at your neighbor and
tell your neighbor you're looking
good.'"
And so, this this two people don't know
each other. So, this guy is telling this
lady, "You're looking good. Better than
yesterday." And the other she's telling
the other guy, "You're looking good.
Better than yesterday."
And they don't know each other, but they
later met outside,
uh shared their phone numbers,
and
tick tick tick tick tick tick tick tick
they got married.
So, you never know. Tell your neighbor,
"You never know."
What else do you feel?
So, when Pastor Ambrose says, "Turn to
your neighbor, your miracle is just
about to happen."
In Jesus' name. Amen. One more big hand
to the Lord.
Shall we pray?
Father, you're a lovely God.
Thank you even for those who are in the
pavilion,
who are listening to us in parents'
room,
who are in this sanctuary and online.
And God, there are some people out there
who desperately need a supernatural
encounter.
And in the name of Jesus,
because of the power of God in our
lives,
Father, we want to send the supernatural
to them.
As I'm praying, Lord, I'm praying for a
supernatural to somebody this afternoon.
Somebody who has just reached at the age
of their life. Somebody who needs an
encounter. And dear Lord, this pastor is
standing up to say, "Lord,
I am standing as a champion to say,
'Lord, let there be a breakthrough.
Let that that answer come. Let your
suddenly happen to God's people.
I'm saying, "Let that suddenly happen to
God's people.
Let that breakthrough come so suddenly
that they will realize it is not man who
made it happen. It is God who just made
it happen."
Father, in the name of Jesus, I pray for
that financial suddenly. For that health
suddenly. For that employment suddenly.
My God, that business suddenly. A
contract that comes through suddenly.
Resources that just show up suddenly. My
God, I decree a suddenly. Your angels
are moving in our midst this afternoon.
And those angels are like lightning.
They pass suddenly carrying the messages
of God. And I pray for somebody today.
They I may have come in so discouraged,
not knowing which way to turn, but Lord,
their suddenly has come. And they are
walking out of here as champions and not
victims. And so Lord, I say thank you
because I as I decree these words, I'm
asking somebody to say, "I receive it."
I'm asking somebody to say, "It is my
portion."
I'm telling somebody to say, "My
suddenly has come."
And there's nothing the devil can do
about it.
Today, I arise
in the name of the master.
In the name of Jesus.
Regardless of my circumstances,
my gates are open.
The angels of the Lord have come.
And the gates will open by themselves.
My breakthrough is here.
My savior is here.
And there's nothing the devil can do
about it.
Somebody better give God a big hand and
say thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you in Jesus' name.
Amen.
Amen. Spirit-led
investment.
Invest in prayer.
Invest in faith.
Invest in the word.
You will never
be disappointed.
In Jesus' name.
One more hand to the Lord
as we thank God
in Jesus' name.
Amen.
Pastor Mashina was part of the team that
went to Chesongoch
and some of them are still on the
highway, still coming. But Pastor
Mashina, come and uh just lead us in the
benediction and release us as we go out
as champions.
Uh do you feel like a champion?
Uh do do you realize you're a champion?
I'm saying, I'm declaring to you, if you
don't realize, now I'm telling you,
you are a champion.
Receive that word.
Not just from me, but from the word of
God.
We are more than
conquerors in Jesus' name. And next
Sunday, you're coming back with a
testimony.
Come on, somebody better give God a big
hand.
Amen.
It was such a joy when I went to Kigali
and we were speaking to the 1,200 young
people. We gave them this cross.
1,200 of them
gave them this cross.
And we know that their lives will not be
the same.
You have not If you have not gotten this
cross, it's in our bookshop, please get
it. Give it to somebody. You never know.
Your investment will not be in vain.
Amen.
Pastor Mashina,
karibu.